# **SUSITHRA S**

# SENIOR DATA ANALYST



- **5** 7092897480
- 2susiss@gmail.com
- **♥** Pollachi

# **SKILLS**

- Core Components
  - Data Quality
  - Taxonomy Development
  - **UNSPSC**
  - ❖ Schema Creation
  - ❖ Data Cleansing
  - Cross Reference
  - ❖ Data Cleansing
  - Spend Analysis
  - Vendor Management
  - ❖ Excel, Microsoft Office
  - Master Data Management

# **LANGUAGES**

English Tamil

## **OBJECTIVE**

Product Data Analyst with 8+ years of experience specializing in Master Data Management. Creative, skilled and accomplished Product Analyst with diverse knowledge of writing contents for various Products. Seeking a position as a Senior Product Analyst in Master Data Management, my skills and proficiency will be utilized

### **EDUCATION**

#### JAY SHRIRAM GROUP OF INSTITUTION, TIRUPUR

BE (Electronics and Communication)

2010 - 2013

---- ANNA UNIVERSITYGPA- 84%

#### • P.A.POLYTECHNIC COLLEGE, POLLACHI

Diploma in ECE

2007 - 2010

---- ANNA UNIVERSITYGPA- 94%

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### PIVOTREE. MUMBAI

Senior Content Analyst

2022 - Now

- \*Analyze and Validate the Data thoroughly and Provide Valid QA Comments as per the Client Requirement.
- \*Hands on Experience in Data Normalization, by Importing and Exporting Data using Internal Tool.
- \*Provide detailed Clarification on Client Queries to Ensure the Smooth Transactions during File Delivery.
- \*Responsible Answering Vendor Team Query for better file Quality
- \*Responsible for Organizing the Data, Handling the Final Delivery File, and Ensuring On-Time Delivery to the Client Team
- \*Adding final files to client workspace.

#### CROWD ANALYTIX, BANGALORE

Contractual Consultant

2021 - 2022

- \*Sourcing and Scraping all the Data from Various Manufacture sites in the specified Structure Formatting Attributes.
- \*Image Processing Process based on the Product Image and Color Coding System.
- \*Auditing the scraped Data and Image Processing File and giving the Valid Comments.

\*Askul (Japanese) Project - Capturing the Data Based on the Competitor Site and Manufacturing Site Creating Attributes, Synonyms, LHN, Product Template.

\*Pilot Project process Involving Classification and Enrichment of MRO Parts based on Standard or Custom Built Schema

#### ALTIUS TECHNOLOGIES, COIMBATORE

Service Support Leader

2014 - 2021

- \*Material Data Enrichment-Web Sourcing, to source the Product by referring varies of Catalogs, Html Pages, and Documents by using MFR Name and Part Number
- \*Material Data Cleansing Extracting the Material Values from Legacy/Input Description in EXCEL by using Attribute Templates/Schema Attributes.
- \*UNSPSC Classification-Classify the Products in Hierarchy Level based on its Application or Types of the Product, to Assign the UNSPSC Code with respect to products.
- \*Taxonomy Assignment/Classification of Materials (Products) and Schema Attributes Creation.
- \*Data Standardization and Data Normalization
- \*Pilot Project process involving classification and enrichment of MRO parts based on Standard or Custom Built Schema
- \*Old data may not be correct or consistent according to new rules for the data, re-processing of existing data as per new rule.
- \*Image Extraction and Part Number Extraction.

#### As a Team Leader

- \*Managed a team of 2 Analyst and 6trainee content writers.
- \*Allocating jobs and workloads to individual staff members based on their ability.
- \*Implementing new initiatives and making sure all staff understand them.
- \*Giving prompt and accurate information on individual staff member performance.
- \*Ensuring a clean, safe and friendly working environment for all team members.
- \*Establishing team and staff targets as reflection of the company's objectives.
- \*Organized training workshops to improve the performance of the members who were lagging behind in terms of performance.